<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Slic3r</title>
  <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/</link>
  <description>STL-to-GCODE translator for RepRap printers</description>
  <generator>BlazeBlogger 1.2.0</generator>
  <item>
    <title>Slic3r 0.8.2 is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/05/17-slic3r-082-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/05/17-slic3r-082-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
Due to an ugly bug slipped in the previous release, a quick replacement is out.    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Slic3r 0.8.1 is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/05/16-slic3r-081-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/05/16-slic3r-081-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
This is a very important update, grab it now and enjoy!
I want to say thanks to the wonderful community that has been helping with feedback, early testing and nice ideas. A lot of people is involved in our open "quality assurance" process!

<h4>New features:</h4>
<ul>
    <li><b>graphical interface for composing multiple objects</b> in one single print (with tools for rotation, scaling etc.)</li>
    <li>new <b>--merge</b> switch to compose multiple object with auto-positioning from command line</li>
    <li>new option to <b>randomize starting points</b> across layers</li>
    <li>automatic detection of additional required perimeters for avoiding haps in domed/sloping objects (the <i>perimeters</i> settings means now <i>minimum perimeters</i> as Slic3r could add more when needed)</li>
    <li><b>sequential printing</b>: print a complete object, then move onto next one, with automatic collision detection</li>
    <li>ability to <b>export STL</b> files of composed plates, as well as a <b>Split</b> command to turn multi-object files into individual objects</li>
    <li>we can read <b>OBJ</b> files now</li>
</ul>

<h4>Improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li><b>very large memory savings</b> and speed boosts, allowing to process high-resolutions files without getting out of memory; also, the number of threads is customizable</li>
    <li>very <b>improved surface quality</b> due to new smoothing algorithms</li>
    <li>the GUI doesn't block while slicing and a <b>Cancel</b> button was added to stop the process</li>
    <li>hole perimeters are extruded in reverse order (from the outermost to the innermost) to get better overhangs</li>
    <li>a slight compensation is applied to avoid small hole shrinkage</li>
    <li>support material now uses honeycomb pattern (much work is still needed on support material)</li>
    <li>retract before changing tool for dual extrusion</li>
</ul>

<h4>Changes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>SVG colors were inverted to better support DLP printing (next versions will carry more settings for SVG export)</li>
</ul>

<h4>Bugfixes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>fixed some GUI memory leaks</li>
    <li>fixed some fatal errors</li>
    <li>fixed a bug causing high memory consumption when infilling every 2 or more layers</li>
    <li>some holes where filled</li>
    <li>some nearly-thin walls were discarded</li>
    <li>removed tiny dots/blobs that were generated sometimes</li>
    <li>bottom layer speed ratio wasn't taken into account when estimating layer time</li>
    <li>omit any G92 E0 when in relative mode</li>
</ul>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Slic3r 0.7.2b is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/04/15-slic3r-072b-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/04/15-slic3r-072b-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2012 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
Due to an error slipped in the 0.7.2 release and quickly reported by early downloaders, I recommend to download the newly-released 0.7.2b now. Sorry!    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>0.7.2 is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/04/14-072-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/04/14-072-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
We have a shiny new beautiful icon now! Thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/cdugd/">Corey Daniels</a> for designing it.

<h4>Major new features:</h4>
<ul>
    <li><b>Honeycomb (hexagonal) infill pattern!</b></li>
    <li><b>SVG export</b> for DLP printers and other purposes</li>
    <li><b>automatic arrangement</b> for printing multiple copies of the same object (thanks Triffid Hunter for contributing this one)</li>
</ul>

<h4>New features:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>new <b>Reslice</b> command in the File menu</li>
    <li>customizable G-code to be executed at layer change</li>
</ul>

<h4>Improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>huge <b>speed boost (20%-50%)</b> and more parallelization of long-running algorithms</li>
    <li>new implementation of <b>support material</b> generation</li>
    <li>don't slow down travel moves when cooling is enabled</li>
    <li>new <i>--threads</i> command line option to set number of parallel jobs</li>
</ul>

<h4>Minor improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>enable G0 automatically for Mach3</li>
    <li>allow decimal values for skirt/duplicate distances and speeds</li>
    <li>added the coordinates of the first non-manifold edge to the warning messages</li>
    <li>only output M109 if there's none in the user-supplied start G-code</li>
    <li>make sure all concentric fill loops are extruded in the same direction to prevent sudden changes of direction</li>
</ul>

<h4>Changes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li><i>--duplicate-x</i> and <i>--duplicate-y</i> were merged into a single <i>--duplicate-grid</i> option</li>
</ul>

<h4>Bugfixes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>some holes were filled</li>
    <li>the <i>No Extrusion</i> mode had no effect</li>
    <li>use M109 for bed control (Makerbot)</li>
    <li>use P instead of S for M106 (Mach3)</li>
    <li>fixed some fatal errors</li>
</ul>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>0.7.1 is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/03/13-071-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/03/13-071-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
<h4>New features:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>new <b>fan always on</b> option</li>
    <li><b>bed temperature control</b> (first layer/other layers)</li>
    <li>Growl notifications</li>
</ul>

<h4>Improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>some algorithms are now less complex (thus faster with larger models)</li>
    <li>fill/perimeter contact is maximized for line pattern</li>
    <li>slowdown is now triggered regardless of whether a fan is used</li>
    <li>allow to use config options in start/end G-code, like for output filename pattern</li>
    <li>throw an error if a user wants to print a 0mm layer</li>
    <li>remove M82/M83 codes for Makerbot output</li>
</ul>

<h4>Changes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>the <i>Use relative E</i> option is now back in the GUI</li>
    <li>remove G0 from the GUI until most firmwares implement it</li>
    <li>avoid G92 codes for Mach3 output</li>
</ul>

<h4>Bugfixes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>retraction wasn't triggered when moving between copies</li>
    <li>a bad "bridge fan end" string was sometimes inserted in G-code</li>
    <li>fixed some fatal errors</li>
    <li>fixed some bogus non-manifold errors happening with certain values of first layer height</li>
    <li>infill extrudates were escaping perimeters sometimes</li>
</ul>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Slic3r 0.7.0 is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/02/12-slic3r-070-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/02/12-slic3r-070-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2012 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
This is a very important update: don't miss it and enjoy the goodies!

<h4>Major new features:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>a <b>new rock-solid slicing algorithm</b>, based on a topological approach, able to process efficiently a wide range of STL files without any warning</li>
    <li>generation of <b>support material</b> (optionally, with a <b>second extruder</b>)</li>
    <li><b>cooling</b> and <b>fan control</b></li>
    <li>ability to read the <b>AMF</b> format</li>
</ul>

<h4>New features:</h4>
<ul>
    <li><b>first layer temperature</b></li>
    <li>support for <b>Makerbot</b> and <b>Mach3</b> G-code flavors</li>
    <li>duplication is performed on generated toolpaths instead of 3D mesh, resulting in a <b>nearly-constant time</b> for any number of object copies</li>
    <li>infill and support material are <b>multi-threaded</b>, so they will take advantage of multiple CPUs/cores</li>
    <li>support for custom post-processing scripts</li>
    <li>new notes field in configuration profiles</li>
</ul>

<h4>Improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>uses 40% less memory</li>
    <li>ability to load multiple config files using the command line</li>
    <li>ask for confirmation when slicing more than one copy</li>
    <li>contours and holes are extruded in the same direction (ccw)</li>
    <li>skein multiple files with a single command from command line</li>
    <li>some compensation for hole shrinkage</li>
</ul>

<h4>Minor improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>do not display the progress dialog as an application-wide modal dialog</li>
    <li>Config files are now portable between Unix and Windows and allow for Unicode characters</li>
    <li>added extrusion multiplier to G-code comments</li>
</ul>

<h4>Bugfixes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>models with rounded walls had small useless infill regions</li>
    <li>small perimeter speed was applied to all holes too, regardless of their size</li>
    <li>fixed some fatal errors</li>
</ul>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>0.6.0 is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/01/11-060-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/01/11-060-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
After much work, a new beefy release of Slic3r is ready for download.

<h4>New features:</h4>
<ul>
    <li><b>thin walls!</b></li>
    <li>new <i>Output Filename Format</i> option to allow for complex output filenames using option values (like <i>foo_3perimeters_0.15height.gcode</i>)</li>
    <li>automatic retraction at the end of the print</li>
</ul>

<h4>Improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>much better overlap between infill and perimeters in those situations where previous version was still producing gaps</li>
    <li>smarter order for hole perimeters to save travel and time</li>
    <li>large internal refactoring (less memory and some speed)</li>
    <li>bridges now have higher priority than other solid regions</li>
    <li>loops are now closed better</li>
    <li>use solid print speed for internal solid layers too</li>
    <li>checkbox in GUI to enable comments in G-code</li>
    <li>warn if no layers were detected</li>
</ul>

<h4>Changes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>Windows package is now distributed as a ZIP file rather than a self-extracting executable</li>
</ul>

<h4>Bugfixes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>some island having no holes and contained in holes themselves were ignored</li>
    <li>fatal error in arc detection code</li>
    <li>wrong month number in output</li>
    <li>small regions were infilled even with fill_density = 0</li>
    <li>fill was escaping perimeters near some corners</li>
    <li>other fatal errors removed, especially when dealing with dirty files</li>
</ul>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Here and there in the Slic3r community</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/01/10-here-and-there-in-the-slic3r-community/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2012/01/10-here-and-there-in-the-slic3r-community/</guid>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2012 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
<p>Okay, Slic3r was born in September and in a few months I was able to bring it beyond what I expected, in terms of features, speed and stability. Things have started to <b>change very quickly</b>, and <b>community</b> is playing a big role in testing and discussing new features.</p>

<p>A <a href="http://forums.reprap.org/list.php?263"><b>Slic3r forum</b></a> was created in the official RepRap forums. Also, about 50 people sit in the <a href="http://webchat.freenode.net/">FreeNode</a> IRC #slic3r channel.</p>

<p>Some notable things appeared in the web recently. Neil Underwood (well known as <a href="http://repraplogphase.blogspot.com/">Spacexula</a>) posted pictures and a video of a print he did on the <a href="http://blog.reprap.org/2011/12/001-layer-height-on-prusa-mendel.html">official RepRap blog</a>. The first outstanding thing is that he reached a <b>0.01mm layer height</b>. The second outstanding thing is that <b>he used Slic3r</b>!</p>

<p>Richard H. (well known as <a href="http://richrap.blogspot.com/">Richrap</a>) is posting a multipart <a href="http://richrap.blogspot.com/2012/01/slic3r-is-nicer-part-1-settings-and.html"><b>illustrated Slic3r guide</b></a> to his colorful blog. It's a very good work, so thank you Rich!</p>

<p>Michael Andresen (well known as <a href="http://captain-slow.dk/">blddk</a>) posted <a href="http://captain-slow.dk/2011/12/29/slic3r-fill-options/
http://captain-slow.dk/2011/12/29/slic3r-fill-options/">some screenshots</a> to show differences between the various <b>fill patterns</b> available in Slic3r. Don't miss the interesting article Gary Hodgson posted about <a href="http://garyhodgson.com/reprap/2012/01/thoughts-on-fill-algorithms/">new possible fill patterns</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://techpaladin.com/">Pointedstick</a> (Nathaniel Graham) posted two good blog articles about <b>high-resolution printing</b>, in which he talks about using Slic3r: <a href="http://techpaladin.com/2011/11/21/getting-all-the-pieces-to-fit-together/">this</a> and <a href="http://techpaladin.com/2011/12/21/nathaniels-guide-to-high-detail-printing/">that</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://brazenartifice.wordpress.com/">Brazen Artifice</a> posted a couple articles about <a href="http://brazenartifice.wordpress.com/2011/12/31/retraction-solution-with-marlin-pronterface-and-slic3r/">retraction</a> and <a href="http://brazenartifice.wordpress.com/2011/12/05/teaching-slic3r-to-remember-your-settings/">preloading last settings</a>.

<p>Sparr posted a picture of an <a href="http://blog.freesideatlanta.org/2011/12/reprap-firmware-comparison-smoother.html">object he printed</a> with and without enabling the <b>native arcs support</b> in Slic3r.</p>

<p>The good <a href="https://github.com/kliment">Kliment Yanev</a> added an option to customize the slicing command in his excellent <a href="https://github.com/kliment/Printrun">Pronterface</a>, to allow for easy <b>integration with Slic3r</b>. (See the <a href="https://github.com/alexrj/Slic3r/blob/master/README.markdown">Slic3r README</a> for guidance.)</p>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Slic3r 0.5.7 is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2011/12/9-slic3r-057-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2011/12/9-slic3r-057-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
<h4>New features:</h4>
<ul>
    <li><i>Slice and save as...</i> command to <b>choose the output file name</b></li>
    <li>Compatibility with Windows XP 64</li>
    <li>Total filament length is written to the output file and showed on command line</li>
</ul>

<h4>Improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li><b>Improved flow and overlapping for solid surfaces</b> by using a better physical model in internal calculations; this gives much <b>higher quality</b> making it less sparse then it was before</li>
    <li>Improved the slicing algorithm; this should <b>reduce the STL warnings</b></li>
    <li>Better overlapping for loops</li>
    <li>Concentric infill now uses the adjusted flow spacing for better surface quality; it also starts infilling always from the center point.</li>
    <li><b>Reduced packages size</b> by 10-20%; they also launch faster</li>
    <li>Always use rectilinear infill for internal solid surfaces</li>
    <li>Limit skirt height to print height</li>
</ul>

<h4>Bugfixes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>Concentric infill was throwing errors</li>
    <li>Extrusion was calculated incorrectly for clock-wise arcs when using the experimental <i>--gcode-arcs</i> option</li>
</ul>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Slic3r 0.5.6 is out!</title>
    <link>http://slic3r.org/blog/2011/12/8-slic3r-056-is-out/</link>
    <guid>http://slic3r.org/blog/2011/12/8-slic3r-056-is-out/</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 00:00:01 GMT</pubDate>
    <description><![CDATA[
<h4>Improvements:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>New extrusion math for more accuracy</li>
    <li>Make sure there are no empty layers at the bottom</li>
    <li>Don't slow down retractions on bottom layer</li>
    <li>Remember last opened directory (until application is closed)</li>
    <li>Don't die when config has unknown options</li>
    <li>More STL files are now accepted</li>
</ul>

<h4>Changes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>Default infill angle is now 45°</li>
    <li>Default retraction speed is now 30mm/s</li>
    <li>Comments in gcode must now be explicitely enabled with the new --gcode-comments option</li>
</ul>

<h4>Bugfixes:</h4>
<ul>
    <li>Objects had slight dimension errors</li>
    <li>Removed fatal errors thrown during infill (small regions and infill every N layers)</li>
    <li>Fixed bolding and font issues on Windows</li>
    <li>Removed fatal error when nothing in a single layer could be parsed</li>
    <li>Duplicate was giving bad number of copies</li>
</ul>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>